





Summary

Jump to Section

12+ Years of total experience in IT sector and in training as a Software developer/Corporate Trainer(online/offline)/Freelancer to deliver software development/training on Cyber Security/Python/Java/C++ and on its related technologies.

7+ years of experience as Corporate Trainer Lead.

Worked as Corporate Trainer Lead at NIIT LTD.

Presently associated in the role of Technical Training Head Galgotias University taking care of Training to undergraduate students for placement for skilling them.

Have worked on Python 3.6.4, Python 2.7.14, Machine Learning, Scikit and M/C implementations.

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Adept in analysing various cyber security case studies, evaluating end-user requirements, custom designing solutions, Debugging & Testing code slices.

Published two SCI papers on Cyber security in reputed European journals like Transactions on emerging telecommunications and technologies.

Excellent team building and troubleshooting skills with abilities in planning and managing resources.

Work Experience

- Galgotais University as Technical Training Head Jan 2019 to Till Date
- NIIT LTD as Corporate Trainer Jun 2013 to Dec 2018
- Aricent Technologies Pvt. Ltd as Software Developer Aug 2008 to May 2013

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Cochin University of Science and Technology (CUST) in 2008

PG: M.Tech (Computer Science and Engineering) from Dr. B.R. Ambedkar National Institute of Technology (NIT) Jalandhar in 2014

Post PG: Ph.D/Doctorate (Computers) from National institute of technology, jalandhar in 2020

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name Version Last Used Experience

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

Cyber Security 2013 7 Year(s) 5 Month(s) Python Programming 2013 7 Year(s) 5 Month(s) Numpy, SciPy, SCIKIT, Pandas 2014 6 Year(s) 4 Month(s) R Programming 2015 5 Year(s) 6 Month(s) SAS programming 2016 4 Year(s) 5 Month(s) MATLAB 2013 7 Year(s) 8 Month(s) MySQL Server 5.3 Mongodb C/C++ windows 7,8,10 WINDOWS SERVER 2008 PyCharm Community Edition PyCharm Professional Edition Netbeans 7.1, Eclipse 3.5 Photoshop, Outlook Xpress MS Office 2013 Microsoft Office 365 ProPlus		 	
Numpy, SciPy, SCIKIT, Pandas R Programming 2015 S Year(s) 6 Month(s) SAS programming 2016 4 Year(s) 5 Month(s) MATLAB 2013 7 Year(s) 8 Month(s) MySQL Server 5.3 Mongodb C/C++ windows 7,8,10 WINDOWS SERVER 2008 PyCharm Community Edition PyCharm Professional Edition Netbeans 7.1, Eclipse 3.5 Photoshop, Outlook Xpress MS Office 2013	Cyber Security	2013	7 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
R Programming 2015 5 Year(s) 6 Month(s) SAS programming 2016 4 Year(s) 5 Month(s) MATLAB 2013 7 Year(s) 8 Month(s) MySQL Server 5.3 Mongodb C/C++ windows 7,8,10 WINDOWS SERVER 2008 PyCharm Community Edition PyCharm Professional Edition Netbeans 7.1, Eclipse 3.5 Photoshop, Outlook Xpress MS Office 2013	Python Programming	2013	7 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
SAS programming 2016 4 Year(s) 5 Month(s) MATLAB 2013 7 Year(s) 8 Month(s) MySQL Server 5.3 Mongodb C/C++ windows 7,8,10 WINDOWS SERVER 2008 PyCharm Community Edition PyCharm Professional Edition Netbeans 7.1, Eclipse 3.5 Photoshop, Outlook Xpress MS Office 2013	Numpy, SciPy, SCIKIT, Pandas	2014	6 Year(s) 4 Month(s)
MATLAB 2013 7 Year(s) 8 Month(s) MySQL Server 5.3 Mongodb C/C++ windows 7,8,10 WINDOWS SERVER 2008 PyCharm Community Edition PyCharm Professional Edition Netbeans 7.1, Eclipse 3.5 Photoshop, Outlook Xpress MS Office 2013	R Programming	2015	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
MySQL Server 5.3 Mongodb C/C++ windows 7,8,10 WINDOWS SERVER 2008 PyCharm Community Edition PyCharm Professional Edition Netbeans 7.1, Eclipse 3.5 Photoshop, Outlook Xpress MS Office 2013	SAS programming	2016	4 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
Mongodb C/C++ windows 7,8,10 WINDOWS SERVER 2008 PyCharm Community Edition PyCharm Professional Edition Netbeans 7.1, Eclipse 3.5 Photoshop, Outlook Xpress MS Office 2013	MATLAB	2013	7 Year(s) 8 Month(s)
C/C++ windows 7,8,10 WINDOWS SERVER 2008 PyCharm Community Edition PyCharm Professional Edition Netbeans 7.1, Eclipse 3.5 Photoshop, Outlook Xpress MS Office 2013	MySQL Server 5.3		
windows 7,8,10 WINDOWS SERVER 2008 PyCharm Community Edition PyCharm Professional Edition Netbeans 7.1, Edipse 3.5 Photoshop, Outlook Xpress MS Office 2013	Mongodb		
WINDOWS SERVER 2008 PyCharm Community Edition PyCharm Professional Edition Netbeans 7.1, Eclipse 3.5 Photoshop, Outlook Xpress MS Office 2013	C/C++		
PyCharm Community Edition PyCharm Professional Edition Netbeans 7.1, Edipse 3.5 Photoshop, Outlook Xpress MS Office 2013	windows 7,8,10		
PyCharm Professional Edition Netbeans 7.1, Eclipse 3.5 Photoshop, Outlook Xpress MS Office 2013	WINDOWS SERVER 2008		
Netbeans 7.1, Eclipse 3.5 Photoshop, Outlook Xpress MS Office 2013	PyCharm Community Edition		
Photoshop, Outlook Xpress MS Office 2013	PyCharm Professional Edition		
MS Office 2013	Netbeans 7.1, Eclipse 3.5		
	Photoshop, Outlook Xpress		
Microsoft Office 365 ProPlus	MS Office 2013		
Welcook clines occ Fior Ide	Microsoft Office 365 ProPlus		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
english				
hindi				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No**

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.